Okay, welcome back everyone. >> So, um the first assignment is out and
>> So, um the first assignment is out and uh as Graham said, we we have credits
uh as Graham said, we we have credits available for you to to work on it for
available for you to to work on it for those of you who are enrolled in the
those of you who are enrolled in the class. Do you folks have any logistic
class. Do you folks have any logistic questions? Cool. Okay. So we talked in
questions? Cool. Okay. So we talked in the last lecture about how agents can uh
the last lecture about how agents can uh choose what to retain within their
choose what to retain within their context window as a way of you know
context window as a way of you know storing information within a task and
storing information within a task and using that to um to determine what's
using that to um to determine what's important to do better within the task.
important to do better within the task. So a big part of today is going to be
So a big part of today is going to be about how can agents go beyond the
about how can agents go beyond the context window and store information
context window and store information across tasks in external stores um that
across tasks in external stores um that will be useful for them to improve
will be useful for them to improve performance on tasks in the future. And
performance on tasks in the future. And this is going to be skill induction. Um,
this is going to be skill induction. Um, and uh, we'll build on some some work
and uh, we'll build on some some work that was done in the past on memory
that was done in the past on memory systems for agents. Um, and show how to
systems for agents. Um, and show how to apply those to to agents. But there's
apply those to to agents. But there's also another view on skills. And skills
also another view on skills. And skills are a way for people to write
are a way for people to write instructions for an agent that can
instructions for an agent that can encode kind of like best practices or
encode kind of like best practices or the knowledge that you have about how a
the knowledge that you have about how a task should be done. And these are
task should be done. And these are actually going to be complimentary to
actually going to be complimentary to each other. Um so we'll cover it just a
each other. Um so we'll cover it just a small amount in this lecture but um you
small amount in this lecture but um you can imagine a system that um is sort of
can imagine a system that um is sort of having a human in the loop um that's
having a human in the loop um that's relying on the agent to uh propose some
relying on the agent to uh propose some potential best practices from the
potential best practices from the experiences that it has a person edit
experiences that it has a person edit those and goes back and forth or vice
those and goes back and forth or vice versa like you know having a skill and
versa like you know having a skill and instruction that's written by a person
instruction that's written by a person be refined by the agent based on
be refined by the agent based on experience. So yeah, it's a lot of
experience. So yeah, it's a lot of different viewpoints, but hopefully by
different viewpoints, but hopefully by the end of the lecture, you'll see how
the end of the lecture, you'll see how they can all sort of fit together.
So let's just start off with some motivation about why you might want to
motivation about why you might want to remember things from one task to
remember things from one task to another. So say that we have an agent
another. So say that we have an agent that's carrying out tasks in a website
that's carrying out tasks in a website like a shopping site and you might give
like a shopping site and you might give it a task like add Sony headphones to my
it a task like add Sony headphones to my wish list. So when we cover guey agents,
wish list. So when we cover guey agents, you'll we'll get into the details of,
you'll we'll get into the details of, you know, the representation space, the
you know, the representation space, the action space for how a system like this
action space for how a system like this works. But at a high level, it's going
works. But at a high level, it's going to be producing actions like um uh
to be producing actions like um uh navigating to the store website, finding
navigating to the store website, finding the search box for it, typing some text
the search box for it, typing some text in that search box, and then clicking
in that search box, and then clicking search. And that's going to be the part
search. And that's going to be the part that like searches for the headphones,
that like searches for the headphones, right? And then we'll do something with
right? And then we'll do something with them. We'll find the ones that match the
them. We'll find the ones that match the request the user had and put them into
request the user had and put them into our wish list.
our wish list. We might have another task that we carry
We might have another task that we carry out in the future like find the wireless
out in the future like find the wireless keyboard price range. And if we're doing
keyboard price range. And if we're doing that on the same site, a lot of the
that on the same site, a lot of the actions are going to be reused, right?
actions are going to be reused, right? We'll go to the store, we'll find the
We'll go to the store, we'll find the search box, we'll search for the
search box, we'll search for the different product but in a similar way
different product but in a similar way and then we'll do something different
and then we'll do something different with it like you know getting the prices
with it like you know getting the prices and reporting those back to the user.
and reporting those back to the user. But if it's difficult for the agent to
But if it's difficult for the agent to figure out how to do this search, once
figure out how to do this search, once it knows how to do it, it should be able
it knows how to do it, it should be able to reuse that knowledge in the future to
to reuse that knowledge in the future to be more effective on future tasks.
be more effective on future tasks. So a lot of structure recurs and today
So a lot of structure recurs and today is going to be about how can we
is going to be about how can we represent this shared structure. So for
represent this shared structure. So for example, is it best to just uh keep kind
example, is it best to just uh keep kind of the raw actions that the agent
of the raw actions that the agent produced when it was carrying out this
produced when it was carrying out this shared subtask or is it better to try to
shared subtask or is it better to try to abstract it into for example a code
abstract it into for example a code function which could be run as a
function which could be run as a blackbox or maybe tested or even like
blackbox or maybe tested or even like hierarchically call other functions.
hierarchically call other functions. We'll also be interested in how can the
We'll also be interested in how can the agent like determine which parts of a
agent like determine which parts of a task should be reused in the future.
task should be reused in the future. And um as we're you know any time we
And um as we're you know any time we have a memory that we're building up
have a memory that we're building up from experience, there's questions about
from experience, there's questions about um how do we grow that memory? Do we are
um how do we grow that memory? Do we are we always adding to it? What happens if
we always adding to it? What happens if we get some conflicting information or
we get some conflicting information or we find a better way to do something? We
we find a better way to do something? We might want to make edits to it. we might
might want to make edits to it. we might want to delete things if they no longer
want to delete things if they no longer seem to apply. So, how can we um kind of
seem to apply. So, how can we um kind of manage the life cycle of these skills um
manage the life cycle of these skills um and these subtask representations that
and these subtask representations that are learned?
are learned? [snorts]
[snorts] So, I'd say there's three general ways
So, I'd say there's three general ways that we can get agents to update. So,
that we can get agents to update. So, the first one we covered in the last
the first one we covered in the last lecture. It's um just what you maintain
lecture. It's um just what you maintain in the context window of the model. So
in the context window of the model. So this is um you know in the standard
this is um you know in the standard React style way. It's the history of the
React style way. It's the history of the past observations and actions that
past observations and actions that you've taken, messages you've gotten
you've taken, messages you've gotten from the user, feedback from the
from the user, feedback from the environment, and you need to you need to
environment, and you need to you need to choose like what to retain given kind of
choose like what to retain given kind of the limitations of the context window
the limitations of the context window and the model's ability to use that. So
and the model's ability to use that. So uh we talked a lot about like compaction
uh we talked a lot about like compaction and methods for managing what's in that
and methods for managing what's in that context window. Today we're going to be
context window. Today we're going to be focusing on storing things outside of
focusing on storing things outside of the context window. So even with like
the context window. So even with like really long context windows that we have
really long context windows that we have now of like a million tokens uh for um
now of like a million tokens uh for um multiple for like carrying out multiple
multiple for like carrying out multiple tasks with an agent um you're going to
tasks with an agent um you're going to exceed that context window and you want
exceed that context window and you want to remember things from past tasks to
to remember things from past tasks to help you on future ones. So if we are
help you on future ones. So if we are storing things outside of the window, um
storing things outside of the window, um that's going to look something like a
that's going to look something like a database um that needs to be managed um
database um that needs to be managed um in some some way or um like a file
in some some way or um like a file system that the agent can access. And uh
system that the agent can access. And uh this lecture is going to be about
this lecture is going to be about methods for um putting things into those
methods for um putting things into those types of storage and um using them and
types of storage and um using them and updating them. And then the final way is
updating them. And then the final way is going to be like actually making uh
going to be like actually making uh updates to the weights of the model.
updates to the weights of the model. Right? So this looks more like standard
Right? So this looks more like standard supervised fine-tuning or reinforcement
supervised fine-tuning or reinforcement learning. We'll cover that in a few
learning. We'll cover that in a few lectures later on. But each of these has
lectures later on. But each of these has like pros and cons. So um I think like a
like pros and cons. So um I think like a main pro of using external artifacts is
main pro of using external artifacts is that they're like they can be ported
that they're like they can be ported across models, right? So if you um have
across models, right? So if you um have a description of the way to search for a
a description of the way to search for a product um that could be used by any one
product um that could be used by any one of a number of different models um
of a number of different models um within an agent framework. Whereas if
within an agent framework. Whereas if you're actually making updates to the
you're actually making updates to the weights of the model that's just an
weights of the model that's just an update for that specific model and it
update for that specific model and it doesn't transfer to others. So external
doesn't transfer to others. So external artifacts are also more inspectable by
artifacts are also more inspectable by people. Um, so you could write down best
people. Um, so you could write down best practices or how to search on a site.
practices or how to search on a site. The agent can use that. The agent could
The agent can use that. The agent could also propose, you know, kind of text for
also propose, you know, kind of text for that and you could look at it and make
that and you could look at it and make changes to it. So there's it's easier to
changes to it. So there's it's easier to kind of like have an interface between
kind of like have an interface between the person and the system if your um
the person and the system if your um method of updating, if your method of
method of updating, if your method of remembering is interpretable.
remembering is interpretable. Any questions about this?
Any questions about this? How many folks have uh have used skills
How many folks have uh have used skills in their interactions with the coding
in their interactions with the coding agent? Like how many of you Okay, so
agent? Like how many of you Okay, so most folks have. How many of you are are
most folks have. How many of you are are writing the skill yourself?
writing the skill yourself? Okay, so maybe about half the folks who
Okay, so maybe about half the folks who are using skills. How many of you have
are using skills. How many of you have uh gotten an agent to write a skill for
uh gotten an agent to write a skill for you? Okay, so a lot of folks actually
you? Okay, so a lot of folks actually have. Yeah. What are some things that
have. Yeah. What are some things that what how what's your experience been for
what how what's your experience been for the agent writing the skills? How often
the agent writing the skills? How often have you been able to use it just right
have you been able to use it just right out of the box? The thing that the agent
out of the box? The thing that the agent constructs
anyone have any spectacular failure cases or spectacular successes? So just
cases or spectacular successes? So just repeating that for the recording like
repeating that for the recording like sometimes the models will write too much
sometimes the models will write too much in the skill like they'll kind of
in the skill like they'll kind of overinfer the what should be done and
overinfer the what should be done and then when that's handed off to another
then when that's handed off to another model it will kind of follow it to the
model it will kind of follow it to the letter and do a lot more than you
letter and do a lot more than you actually wanted it to.
actually wanted it to. >> Any other examples from folks?
>> Cool. Oh yeah, go ahead. I mean in cases when you're like trying to like a
when you're like trying to like a production issue for like a particular
production issue for like a particular system if you give it like three or four
system if you give it like three or four support
support and you tell it that look at how people
and you tell it that look at how people have this issue in the past create a
have this issue in the past create a skill for yourself
skill for yourself other agents could use to it in the same
other agents could use to it in the same way
way >> and that's
>> and that's very
very >> oh nice
>> oh nice >> okay cool yeah so instructing it to like
>> okay cool yeah so instructing it to like get write the instructions for another
get write the instructions for another agent it's good enough it's sort of like
agent it's good enough it's sort of like simulating what the agent would do.
simulating what the agent would do. Yeah, that's interesting. I've sometimes
Yeah, that's interesting. I've sometimes found that the models are like pretty
found that the models are like pretty bad at kind of like simulating the
bad at kind of like simulating the theory of mind that you know another
theory of mind that you know another person or an agent would have when they
person or an agent would have when they like look at instructions, but they get
like look at instructions, but they get a lot better when you prompt them to do
a lot better when you prompt them to do that. Cool.
that. Cool. Okay.
Okay. Yeah. So, a few different like types of
Yeah. So, a few different like types of experience that we might want to retain
experience that we might want to retain for agents. So the first is like the
for agents. So the first is like the episode and this is you know just the
episode and this is you know just the sequence of observations that you get
sequence of observations that you get from the environment from the user and
from the environment from the user and the actions that are taken and this is
the actions that are taken and this is sort of like the maximum fidelity right
sort of like the maximum fidelity right you're just you're retaining everything
you're just you're retaining everything you have all the specifics of that
you have all the specifics of that particular environment and the
particular environment and the particular instructions that the user
particular instructions that the user gave also going to be like the most
gave also going to be like the most costly right it'll need the most tokens
costly right it'll need the most tokens to represent and you probably don't need
to represent and you probably don't need all of that right? Like uh just like
all of that right? Like uh just like when we're doing you know supervised
when we're doing you know supervised learning we don't want to retain every
learning we don't want to retain every detail we want to abstract to the things
detail we want to abstract to the things that matter to generalize um in the
that matter to generalize um in the future.
future. So we could also retain some facts like
So we could also retain some facts like um some knowledge about the environment
um some knowledge about the environment um or about the user and in the early
um or about the user and in the early work on memory systems uh a lot of it
work on memory systems uh a lot of it was focused on retaining facts. So like
was focused on retaining facts. So like a user is interacting with an assistant
a user is interacting with an assistant and maybe gives some personal
and maybe gives some personal information like how old they are or
information like how old they are or where they live. The system can retain
where they live. The system can retain that in its memory and then use that
that in its memory and then use that fact to improve future interactions. If
fact to improve future interactions. If you've um used uh like Anthropic or
you've um used uh like Anthropic or Chatbt's uh memory systems, uh they're
Chatbt's uh memory systems, uh they're doing this basically, right? Like you
doing this basically, right? Like you can go into the settings, you can view
can go into the settings, you can view the memory that they have about you and
the memory that they have about you and there's, you know, a text representation
there's, you know, a text representation there from a model that's produced those
there from a model that's produced those facts um from your past interactions.
facts um from your past interactions. Looks a little bit like compaction in
Looks a little bit like compaction in some way. It's generated by an LLM. It
some way. It's generated by an LLM. It gets stored in this external thing.
gets stored in this external thing. And then the final one is more specific
And then the final one is more specific to agents. So it's about like how do you
to agents. So it's about like how do you do part of a task um in a way that's
do part of a task um in a way that's abstracted from the details of the task.
abstracted from the details of the task. So like in the example we looked at
So like in the example we looked at before, how do you search for products
before, how do you search for products on a particular website without maybe
on a particular website without maybe retaining the details of searching, you
retaining the details of searching, you know, the particular product that you
know, the particular product that you searched for? And so there's a lot of
searched for? And so there's a lot of choices about how you would represent a
choices about how you would represent a skill. Is it just text? Is it kind of
skill. Is it just text? Is it kind of the actual actions that you took? Um or
the actual actions that you took? Um or could it even be code?
could it even be code? And of course, skills are only going to
And of course, skills are only going to be useful if you're going to be doing
be useful if you're going to be doing the same subtask more than once.
So we could think about like um memory and skills and the intersection between
and skills and the intersection between them. So memory is just something that
them. So memory is just something that we're saving from the agents
we're saving from the agents interaction. So for example, what's a
interaction. So for example, what's a previous product that you purchased on a
previous product that you purchased on a site? A skill would be reusable
site? A skill would be reusable knowledge about how to act in an
knowledge about how to act in an environment. um which could be
environment. um which could be represented in one of a variety of ways.
represented in one of a variety of ways. Like it could be, you know, if you're
Like it could be, you know, if you're releasing a um application um by pushing
releasing a um application um by pushing it to production, here's a checklist
it to production, here's a checklist that you need to go through before you
that you need to go through before you do that. So, a skill could be written by
do that. So, a skill could be written by a person like in this example. But we
a person like in this example. But we could also have um a combination of
could also have um a combination of memory and skills. So we could induce
memory and skills. So we could induce skills from the agents past experiences
skills from the agents past experiences and store those um and then use those to
and store those um and then use those to hopefully do better in the future. So if
hopefully do better in the future. So if the agent searched successfully for a
the agent searched successfully for a product in the past um and uh yeah and
product in the past um and uh yeah and if it was successful, if we think that
if it was successful, if we think that it was successful, then we could pull
it was successful, then we could pull out something that looks like a skill to
out something that looks like a skill to guide the agent in the future. And we'll
guide the agent in the future. And we'll get a lot more concrete about what this
get a lot more concrete about what this looks like through the rest of the
looks like through the rest of the lecture.
So we can think about skills as instructions where uh skills as
instructions where uh skills as instructions might be written by a
instructions might be written by a person um for encoding their own you
person um for encoding their own you know preferences or might be
know preferences or might be organization policies like this is the
organization policies like this is the way that we write and test code in this
way that we write and test code in this particular company. Um and human
particular company. Um and human authored skills um we know where they
authored skills um we know where they came from. we have more maybe control
came from. we have more maybe control over the quality but it takes you know a
over the quality but it takes you know a lot of time to write them and to
lot of time to write them and to maintain them. If we're learning skills
maintain them. If we're learning skills then the agent is producing them. Um and
then the agent is producing them. Um and this is helpful because we can do this
this is helpful because we can do this in an automated way. Maybe we can have
in an automated way. Maybe we can have like a loop where we induce the skill.
like a loop where we induce the skill. We try to use the skill to redo the same
We try to use the skill to redo the same tasks. We see if things get better on a
tasks. We see if things get better on a metric. Um, but it can be, you know,
metric. Um, but it can be, you know, potentially noisy too and have, you
potentially noisy too and have, you know, especially if you're using the
know, especially if you're using the skills for some other agent like we
skills for some other agent like we talked about in those examples everybody
talked about in those examples everybody gave, um, it could maybe have unintended
gave, um, it could maybe have unintended consequences too.
Okay, so let's talk first about uh, humanridden skills and um, the standards
humanridden skills and um, the standards for these and the ways that they're used
for these and the ways that they're used in incurrent agents. So probably a lot
in incurrent agents. So probably a lot of it sounds like a lot of you have
of it sounds like a lot of you have experience with this already. Uh so
experience with this already. Uh so maybe you've been using these in the
maybe you've been using these in the context of an example kind of like this.
context of an example kind of like this. Uh there's this nice blog post from open
Uh there's this nice blog post from open hands that has guidance on using skills.
hands that has guidance on using skills. Um for those of you who um who haven't
Um for those of you who um who haven't used skills yet or if you you know like
used skills yet or if you you know like some suggestions on how to uh how to
some suggestions on how to uh how to have best practices for creating and
have best practices for creating and using skills. But they have this
using skills. But they have this motivating motivating example of say
motivating motivating example of say that you find yourself like always
that you find yourself like always giving similar instructions to a coding
giving similar instructions to a coding agent. Um so you um want the you want to
agent. Um so you um want the you want to check the code that has been written
check the code that has been written using one of a couple different
using one of a couple different llinters. You want to give type hints.
llinters. You want to give type hints. You want to use a particular type of
You want to use a particular type of dock strings. And you want to apply
dock strings. And you want to apply piest to all the functions. So if you're
piest to all the functions. So if you're always doing this, you could always type
always doing this, you could always type this guidance into the system. Um, but
this guidance into the system. Um, but you know, a kind of natural and faster
you know, a kind of natural and faster way to do this would be to just have the
way to do this would be to just have the like store the guidance as a text file
like store the guidance as a text file and then have the agent use that
and then have the agent use that guidance um as an instruction. So you
guidance um as an instruction. So you should reach for a skill when you want
should reach for a skill when you want to do something repeatedly following
to do something repeatedly following kind of like a fixed specification. And
kind of like a fixed specification. And the agent's going to choose how to
the agent's going to choose how to interpret this specification in context,
interpret this specification in context, but the um general instruction is the
but the um general instruction is the same.
And the way that this is implemented in the current standard for skills um which
the current standard for skills um which is called agent skills is just as a
is called agent skills is just as a collection of files which the agent is
collection of files which the agent is able to read.
And here's an example of of that. So if we are constructing a skill for Python
we are constructing a skill for Python review um we'll have a folder which has
review um we'll have a folder which has a structure like this. So skills have
a structure like this. So skills have this standard structure where they'll
this standard structure where they'll have a skill.md file and you have to
have a skill.md file and you have to have that. Skill.md um is a markdown
have that. Skill.md um is a markdown file that starts with um some YAML
file that starts with um some YAML metadata. So you need to have a name for
metadata. So you need to have a name for the skill and you need to have a short
the skill and you need to have a short description uh which is going to give
description uh which is going to give guidance to the language model about
guidance to the language model about when the skill should be applied. And
when the skill should be applied. And we'll see in a slide or two about how
we'll see in a slide or two about how the model gets access to this
the model gets access to this information in the YAML header. And then
information in the YAML header. And then um after the header you'll have a much
um after the header you'll have a much more detailed description of um how the
more detailed description of um how the skill should be applied which would for
skill should be applied which would for example you know list um here are all
example you know list um here are all the llinters that you should apply
the llinters that you should apply here's how testing should be done and so
here's how testing should be done and so on. So you have to have skill.mmd. You
on. So you have to have skill.mmd. You also have a few other um folders which
also have a few other um folders which are optional but can contain some extra
are optional but can contain some extra resources for the agent to use as it
resources for the agent to use as it carries out the skill. So there's
carries out the skill. So there's scripts which has executable code. So
scripts which has executable code. So for example, if you had like a Python
for example, if you had like a Python script that would run a llinter, you
script that would run a llinter, you could put it in there and then describe
could put it in there and then describe it in this skill.md file. There's also
it in this skill.md file. There's also references, which would be sort of like
references, which would be sort of like supplementary documentation that maybe
supplementary documentation that maybe you don't you you don't need to use it
you don't you you don't need to use it every time you use the skill. Um, but
every time you use the skill. Um, but you'll have maybe a reference to that
you'll have maybe a reference to that documentation in the skill file. The
documentation in the skill file. The agent could load it as needed from the
agent could load it as needed from the references folder. And then assets
references folder. And then assets basically just has like, you know,
basically just has like, you know, additional templates or resources like
additional templates or resources like if you're, you know, doing something
if you're, you know, doing something that involves like Ginga and you need
that involves like Ginga and you need the agent to load that conditionally.
the agent to load that conditionally. So this can be a lot of information,
So this can be a lot of information, right? And we um don't want to fill up
right? And we um don't want to fill up the context window of the model um with
the context window of the model um with all of the possible skills that it could
all of the possible skills that it could use. So there's a mechanism called
use. So there's a mechanism called progressive disclosure which is going to
progressive disclosure which is going to just show relevant parts of skills to
just show relevant parts of skills to the agent as they're needed. So the
the agent as they're needed. So the first level is um the metadata in this
first level is um the metadata in this YAML file. Uh so the name and the
YAML file. Uh so the name and the description and that's always going to
description and that's always going to be um shown to the model in the system
be um shown to the model in the system prompt if the skill is loaded if it's
prompt if the skill is loaded if it's available to the model to use. So you
available to the model to use. So you need to be kind of concise in this uh
need to be kind of concise in this uh description. Um so that if you have a
description. Um so that if you have a lot of skills you don't fill things up
lot of skills you don't fill things up too much.
too much. There's the second level which is the
There's the second level which is the rest of the text in the markdown file
rest of the text in the markdown file and um that'll be loaded conditionally
and um that'll be loaded conditionally if the model decides that the skill is
if the model decides that the skill is relevant um and uh decides to read the
relevant um and uh decides to read the rest of the file via a tool call. We'll
rest of the file via a tool call. We'll see an example of that in a minute. And
see an example of that in a minute. And then the next level is sort of like all
then the next level is sort of like all the resources in here which will also be
the resources in here which will also be loaded um using tool calls. So you kind
loaded um using tool calls. So you kind of need to have enough information in
of need to have enough information in the skill.md file for the model to be
the skill.md file for the model to be aware that it should look into these
aware that it should look into these additional folders to get more resources
additional folders to get more resources um when it's carrying out the skill. Any
um when it's carrying out the skill. Any questions about this and you'll
questions about this and you'll implement this in assignment one or
implement this in assignment one or maybe some of you are already starting
maybe some of you are already starting on implementing that.
on implementing that. >> Yeah.
like what if that takes too much of that effect performance?
effect performance? >> Yeah. So if you have a lot of skills
>> Yeah. So if you have a lot of skills even if the skill metadata is pretty
even if the skill metadata is pretty short could it affect performance? Yeah,
short could it affect performance? Yeah, it definitely can. Um so you want to
it definitely can. Um so you want to keep the number of skills somewhat small
keep the number of skills somewhat small and maybe just load them conditionally.
and maybe just load them conditionally. um in one of the state-of-the-art
um in one of the state-of-the-art agents, Hermes agent, I think the I'm
agents, Hermes agent, I think the I'm not sure the number of skills, but like
not sure the number of skills, but like the total length of the skill
the total length of the skill descriptions in the system prompt is
descriptions in the system prompt is like 3,000 tokens. Um there's some
like 3,000 tokens. Um there's some papers that we'll see in a little bit
papers that we'll see in a little bit that show that if you have too many
that show that if you have too many skills, um it can make performance
skills, um it can make performance worse. Like adding in irrelevant skills
worse. Like adding in irrelevant skills can drop performance um because, you
can drop performance um because, you know, the context gets longer. The model
know, the context gets longer. The model might be distracted by things that are
might be distracted by things that are actually irrelevant. So yeah, you
actually irrelevant. So yeah, you definitely need to be careful about the
definitely need to be careful about the number of skills, but um I think it
number of skills, but um I think it would be pretty rare to have like 10,000
would be pretty rare to have like 10,000 or a thousand skills. Generally, it's,
or a thousand skills. Generally, it's, you know, smaller and you would maybe
you know, smaller and you would maybe load skills as needed for like the
load skills as needed for like the software tasks that you're carrying out.
software tasks that you're carrying out. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> How sensitive are those triggers?
>> How sensitive are those triggers? >> Yeah, that's a great question. How
>> Yeah, that's a great question. How sensitive are the triggers? So the the
sensitive are the triggers? So the the triggers will be tool calls that will be
triggers will be tool calls that will be generated by the model. And so whether
generated by the model. And so whether they get called or not is a function is
they get called or not is a function is totally dependent on the model. Um and
totally dependent on the model. Um and you know the model's ability to predict
you know the model's ability to predict that it should be triggered based on the
that it should be triggered based on the past context and what it knows about the
past context and what it knows about the skill. So that you know depends on the
skill. So that you know depends on the model depends on the description you
model depends on the description you write and um that's why we need
write and um that's why we need evaluations for this. Um and one of the
evaluations for this. Um and one of the papers that we'll look at takes a step
papers that we'll look at takes a step in that direction.
in that direction. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah. like a standardized name.
>> Yeah. Uh skill.md is a standardized name. So the the standard is called the
name. So the the standard is called the um I think the agent skills standard and
um I think the agent skills standard and um you like models agents are trained to
um you like models agents are trained to to use that agent frameworks are trained
to use that agent frameworks are trained to load that. Um so yeah you um if you
to load that. Um so yeah you um if you want to use an alternate format well
want to use an alternate format well first put it you know as close to this
first put it you know as close to this as you can but you could do you know if
as you can but you could do you know if you have particular if you have
you have particular if you have particular um things that you want like
particular um things that you want like in the references folder you could
in the references folder you could describe them in skill.md and like all
describe them in skill.md and like all this is just going to be instructions to
this is just going to be instructions to the language model so it could be robust
the language model so it could be robust to other configurations also especially
to other configurations also especially if you describe them.
if you describe them. >> Yeah. Why are
>> Yeah, why markdown? It it is a balance of machine and human readability, I
of machine and human readability, I think.
>> Yeah, that's a great question. Could there be better formats than than
there be better formats than than skill.md?
skill.md? Yeah. Do you have things in mind?
Yeah. Do you have things in mind? I think like um so uh I mean it's just
I think like um so uh I mean it's just like linear right um it's you can have
like linear right um it's you can have hyperlinks which is good you can embed
hyperlinks which is good you can embed images too um
images too um >> yeah um but uh like it's difficult to
>> yeah um but uh like it's difficult to you know represent things that are
you know represent things that are dynamic so like maybe you want to
dynamic so like maybe you want to illustrate to the model like um
illustrate to the model like um different ways the data could be
different ways the data could be visualized um you know maybe that would
visualized um you know maybe that would be better with like a JavaScript
be better with like a JavaScript interactive JavaScript application or
interactive JavaScript application or something like that. Um, yeah, you
something like that. Um, yeah, you could, you know, have that be sort of
could, you know, have that be sort of like a code file here that gets
like a code file here that gets executed. Um, but and maybe like
executed. Um, but and maybe like referenced in the markdown. Um, so I
referenced in the markdown. Um, so I think like markdown is sort of the best
think like markdown is sort of the best attempt at having something that's
attempt at having something that's general and like readable, but then you
general and like readable, but then you would rely on the language model to
would rely on the language model to interpret other formats.
interpret other formats. >> I think in the scientific literature
>> I think in the scientific literature that uh Daniel's going to talk about,
that uh Daniel's going to talk about, there's basically two ways. There's
there's basically two ways. There's textual skills and programmatic skills
textual skills and programmatic skills and the textual skills appear in the
and the textual skills appear in the markdown and the programmatic skills
markdown and the programmatic skills appear in the script. So it kind of it's
appear in the script. So it kind of it's pretty broad if you consider those.
pretty broad if you consider those. >> Yeah. Cool.
>> Yeah. Cool. >> Yeah.
>> Yeah. >> Does anyone do
>> Does anyone do to not have to put it all in context?
to not have to put it all in context? For example, if you're making an agent
For example, if you're making an agent that modifies cloud infrastructure, you
that modifies cloud infrastructure, you work at some big bank and have a billion
work at some big bank and have a billion things in AWS and it would be nice to be
things in AWS and it would be nice to be able to just ask the model to modify
able to just ask the model to modify something, but then because it's a
something, but then because it's a billion things, you can just have a
billion things, you can just have a billion tools for every small component
billion tools for every small component available. Yes.
available. Yes. >> So looks like something
>> So looks like something would
would do. Yeah, definitely in some of the
do. Yeah, definitely in some of the research papers that so the question was
research papers that so the question was like do people retrieve from large
like do people retrieve from large collections of skills. Um and yeah
collections of skills. Um and yeah definitely in some of the research
definitely in some of the research papers that we'll look at um they do
papers that we'll look at um they do that um either using you know just like
that um either using you know just like a text embedding based retrieval or
a text embedding based retrieval or doing something that's more kind of like
doing something that's more kind of like domain conditional like we know these
domain conditional like we know these skills apply to this site so when we're
skills apply to this site so when we're interacting with that site we'll load
interacting with that site we'll load those skills. Yeah, I imagine production
those skills. Yeah, I imagine production systems do this too, but um yeah, I
systems do this too, but um yeah, I don't have any references off the top of
don't have any references off the top of my head for that. Cool. Okay, so we'll
my head for that. Cool. Okay, so we'll uh just uh kind of quickly to show you
uh just uh kind of quickly to show you how progressive disclosure works. Um we
how progressive disclosure works. Um we first need to give the model access to
first need to give the model access to this level one, right? Let it know what
this level one, right? Let it know what skills are available. And you'll have a
skills are available. And you'll have a system prompt that looks something like
system prompt that looks something like this. This is just taken from Hermes
this. This is just taken from Hermes agent which is sort of like a standard
agent which is sort of like a standard open- source um agent that is able to
open- source um agent that is able to use and induce skills and you'll um kind
use and induce skills and you'll um kind of describe what skills are. Uh you'll
of describe what skills are. Uh you'll tell the model about this skill view
tell the model about this skill view tool which it could use to read the rest
tool which it could use to read the rest of the markdown file and then you'll
of the markdown file and then you'll list out all the skills that you have.
list out all the skills that you have. So there's just two skills here. Um,
So there's just two skills here. Um, there's a code quality skill and a
there's a code quality skill and a workflow skill. And that's just the YAML
workflow skill. And that's just the YAML metadata from those skill files.
So, um, the model is able to use tool calls to, you know, expand the rest of
calls to, you know, expand the rest of the skill. And here's what that might
the skill. And here's what that might look like. So, it always has the index
look like. So, it always has the index of skills in the system prompt, but it
of skills in the system prompt, but it could choose to make a tool call to open
could choose to make a tool call to open the Python review skill. um if that
the Python review skill. um if that seems relevant to you know the user
seems relevant to you know the user asked for a review of some Python code
asked for a review of some Python code and then it's going to like um you know
and then it's going to like um you know get that markdown file insert it as a
get that markdown file insert it as a message to the system as an observation
message to the system as an observation the result of that skill view tool. Um
the result of that skill view tool. Um the system might choose to run something
the system might choose to run something from the scripts directory um and then
from the scripts directory um and then it'll get the result of running that
it'll get the result of running that script as an observation put it in the
script as an observation put it in the window um and might choose to you know
window um and might choose to you know like view additional files within that
like view additional files within that skill package.
Okay. So yeah, we these questions that we had about like you know could
we had about like you know could additional skills hurt um are skills
additional skills hurt um are skills being triggered in the right place. Uh
being triggered in the right place. Uh we answer questions like this by
we answer questions like this by building evaluations and um the the work
building evaluations and um the the work on this is a little bit um new. It's
on this is a little bit um new. It's sort of ongoing but um a really great
sort of ongoing but um a really great first effort in the space is called
first effort in the space is called skills bench and what they do is they um
skills bench and what they do is they um collect a bunch of skills uh from uh
collect a bunch of skills uh from uh various sources online. they actually
various sources online. they actually get like 2 million skills. Um, and
get like 2 million skills. Um, and they'll also have people write tasks
they'll also have people write tasks which seem like they could benefit from
which seem like they could benefit from skills. Uh, and so they'll like get 400
skills. Uh, and so they'll like get 400 tasks and um those are going to be
tasks and um those are going to be written independently from the skills,
written independently from the skills, but they'll have the task annotators
but they'll have the task annotators choose from this pool of skills ones
choose from this pool of skills ones that seem like they could apply to the
that seem like they could apply to the tasks. And so you'll have kind of like a
tasks. And so you'll have kind of like a small set of curated skills. um and
small set of curated skills. um and you'll supply those skills to an agent
you'll supply those skills to an agent as it's trying to solve the task and
as it's trying to solve the task and they'll evaluate this on like um you
they'll evaluate this on like um you know four different agent frameworks uh
know four different agent frameworks uh with I think like 18 models something
with I think like 18 models something like that and they'll just see like does
like that and they'll just see like does having the skills um improve performance
having the skills um improve performance over not having the skills across all
over not having the skills across all the tasks for a given agent framework
the tasks for a given agent framework and model combination right so this will
and model combination right so this will evaluate you know it'll implicitly
evaluate you know it'll implicitly evaluate the skill quality but will be
evaluate the skill quality but will be designed to evaluate is a model and
designed to evaluate is a model and framework able to you know use the
framework able to you know use the skills appropriately and they're trying
skills appropriately and they're trying to choose the skills. So they have like
to choose the skills. So they have like a filter um which checks to see that for
a filter um which checks to see that for a small subset of models the performance
a small subset of models the performance on the tasks does improve when you give
on the tasks does improve when you give models access to the skills and then
models access to the skills and then you're seeing if that's also true for
you're seeing if that's also true for kind of a wider set of frameworks and
kind of a wider set of frameworks and models.
Yeah. Does the general setup make sense? Cool.
Does the general setup make sense? Cool. So on average, you know, with this cur
So on average, you know, with this cur curated set of um skills, uh the average
curated set of um skills, uh the average pass rates on these tasks using like
pass rates on these tasks using like humanridden verification criteria does
humanridden verification criteria does increase. And so you can see like the
increase. And so you can see like the solid bars to the shaded bars across a
solid bars to the shaded bars across a bunch of different models um and
bunch of different models um and frameworks. Um but actually uh ski like
frameworks. Um but actually uh ski like tasks that require fewer skills to solve
tasks that require fewer skills to solve benefit more from having the skills
benefit more from having the skills available than ones that require more
available than ones that require more skills. Um and so this is partly a
skills. Um and so this is partly a difficulty thing but also partly that
difficulty thing but also partly that the models might be getting distracted
the models might be getting distracted by having more skills available. And you
by having more skills available. And you could imagine that it's getting much
could imagine that it's getting much worse with like a much larger number of
worse with like a much larger number of skills. Um we'll see some more evidence
skills. Um we'll see some more evidence for that later on in the lecture.
for that later on in the lecture. And actually skills still hurt on a
And actually skills still hurt on a number of the tasks for particular model
number of the tasks for particular model types. Um so the model might be using
types. Um so the model might be using the skill inappropriately which could
the skill inappropriately which could actually make it do the task in a way
actually make it do the task in a way different than what the person
different than what the person specified. So this kind of motivates the
specified. So this kind of motivates the importance of like checking to see if
importance of like checking to see if the skills that you wrote are actually
the skills that you wrote are actually making your outputs better.
So skills can come from, you know, a bunch of different sources. They could
bunch of different sources. They could be bundled with the harness. Um, they
be bundled with the harness. Um, they could be written by a person. Um, and a
could be written by a person. Um, and a lot of you have done this, it sounds
lot of you have done this, it sounds like, and you then, you know, kind of
like, and you then, you know, kind of install it in a in a way that's
install it in a in a way that's specified by the framework that you're
specified by the framework that you're using, but they can also be created by
using, but they can also be created by the agent. And, um, Hermes has a skill
the agent. And, um, Hermes has a skill manage tool. um open hands as a skill
manage tool. um open hands as a skill creator uh command that help work you
creator uh command that help work you through the process of creating a skill.
through the process of creating a skill. And when you're creating a skill, I
And when you're creating a skill, I think it's really important to base that
think it's really important to base that skill on some prior interactions that
skill on some prior interactions that you've had rather than trying to just do
you've had rather than trying to just do it sort of a priori. Um and actually
it sort of a priori. Um and actually there's some results in the skills bench
there's some results in the skills bench paper that show that models when they're
paper that show that models when they're tasked to create a skill by themselves
tasked to create a skill by themselves just based on a task description,
just based on a task description, they're really bad at it. and it
they're really bad at it. and it actually makes performance worse. So, as
actually makes performance worse. So, as a person, you're probably better because
a person, you're probably better because you kind of like know the way that you
you kind of like know the way that you want it to be done, but it's generally
want it to be done, but it's generally best to base it on, you know, past
best to base it on, you know, past things that you've done because when
things that you've done because when you're doing a task, it'll reveal some
you're doing a task, it'll reveal some things about the way you want it to be
things about the way you want it to be done that you might not know in advance.
done that you might not know in advance. So there's a nice case study of this um
So there's a nice case study of this um from the open hands blog post on how do
from the open hands blog post on how do you like so you have this code review
you like so you have this code review skill that you've created. How do you
skill that you've created. How do you check and see if it's working and then
check and see if it's working and then improve it if necessary.
improve it if necessary. So this is focused on like reviewing
So this is focused on like reviewing poll requests and what what you could do
poll requests and what what you could do is like um after the review is produced
is like um after the review is produced by the agent then a person is going to
by the agent then a person is going to go through the poll request and look at
go through the poll request and look at each of those review comments and either
each of those review comments and either address them or not. And you can apply a
address them or not. And you can apply a modelbased judge after that and count up
modelbased judge after that and count up how many of these were like actually
how many of these were like actually used by the person which will give you a
used by the person which will give you a sense of how good the pull request was.
sense of how good the pull request was. And you can like um do this over a large
And you can like um do this over a large number of pull requests that were
number of pull requests that were created and then reviewed by the agent
created and then reviewed by the agent using this skill. And um if you do this
using this skill. And um if you do this over um you know like hundreds or
over um you know like hundreds or thousands of examples, you'll get a lot
thousands of examples, you'll get a lot of evidence about what's working and
of evidence about what's working and what's not, you can summarize all of
what's not, you can summarize all of that with a reasoning model um and use
that with a reasoning model um and use that to like for example identify that
that to like for example identify that it's not helpful to um you know produce
it's not helpful to um you know produce code that ignores the repo conventions.
code that ignores the repo conventions. people did like incorporate those
people did like incorporate those changes quite a bit. And then you could
changes quite a bit. And then you could like have the model propose some updates
like have the model propose some updates to the skill file that will make the you
to the skill file that will make the you know reviews produced by the system more
know reviews produced by the system more likely to be incorporated by the person.
Okay. So next we'll talk about how do we get
So next we'll talk about how do we get models to automatically remember things
models to automatically remember things from their past experience and then
from their past experience and then we'll use that to like build on um to
we'll use that to like build on um to talk about inducing skills from
talk about inducing skills from experience.
experience. So this is this is an old paper. This is
So this is this is an old paper. This is from 2023 um but it was pretty
from 2023 um but it was pretty influential. Um and it's uh it's one of
influential. Um and it's uh it's one of the first papers it's called MEMGPT.
the first papers it's called MEMGPT. It's one of the first papers to uh
It's one of the first papers to uh [snorts]
[snorts] introduce a way that you can manage
introduce a way that you can manage memory outside of the context window of
memory outside of the context window of a language model. So this is like a
a language model. So this is like a really a systems inspired paper. I think
really a systems inspired paper. I think we talked about a couple lectures ago
we talked about a couple lectures ago about you know kind of having like
about you know kind of having like memory hierarchies like you know
memory hierarchies like you know something that is fast to access which
something that is fast to access which for the language model is the context
for the language model is the context window and then something that's like
window and then something that's like larger but but slower and in this
larger but but slower and in this setting that would be like an external
setting that would be like an external store of of facts and back when this
store of of facts and back when this paper was written uh a few years ago
paper was written uh a few years ago context windows were even shorter like
context windows were even shorter like you know 8,000 tokens um so this sort of
you know 8,000 tokens um so this sort of approach was really well motivated even
approach was really well motivated even for just interacting with like an
for just interacting with like an assistant system. Um nowadays you know
assistant system. Um nowadays you know our context windows are larger but what
our context windows are larger but what you want to store in them is also much
you want to store in them is also much larger. So this sort of approach is
larger. So this sort of approach is pretty well motivated for agents too.
pretty well motivated for agents too. But the basic idea here is that you're
But the basic idea here is that you're going to have like a um you'll have you
going to have like a um you'll have you know the system instructions which don't
know the system instructions which don't get updated. you'll have a working
get updated. you'll have a working context um which is going to uh pull
context um which is going to uh pull things from an external memory um and
things from an external memory um and also you'll be storing things to this
also you'll be storing things to this external memory and those reads and
external memory and those reads and writes are going to be controlled by
writes are going to be controlled by tool calls from the model
tool calls from the model and um you'll also you know have like a
and um you'll also you know have like a separate storage for the actual messages
separate storage for the actual messages that the system received um but that's
that the system received um but that's going to be controlled in a pretty
going to be controlled in a pretty similar way to this uh this memory over
similar way to this uh this memory over fax
fax So, what this actually looks like, sorry
So, what this actually looks like, sorry it's a little bit hard to read with the
it's a little bit hard to read with the brightness in here, but like if you um
brightness in here, but like if you um you might uh have an interaction with
you might uh have an interaction with the model where the user like mentions
the model where the user like mentions six flags and um the system could
six flags and um the system could produce a tool call that searches within
produce a tool call that searches within this storage for past mentions of six
this storage for past mentions of six flags from its past interactions. It'll
flags from its past interactions. It'll take those and it'll put them into this
take those and it'll put them into this like working context. Um and then the
like working context. Um and then the model um this working context is stored
model um this working context is stored within the context window of the
within the context window of the language model. So the model will be
language model. So the model will be able to use those as it outputs its
able to use those as it outputs its response.
But it's important to be able to do more than just like add to memory because for
than just like add to memory because for example like um maybe you're talking to
example like um maybe you're talking to the system about your job. you say I
the system about your job. you say I work at X, but then if you change jobs
work at X, but then if you change jobs later on, you want the system to be able
later on, you want the system to be able to like use the latest information.
to like use the latest information. And um this paper called me zero uh
And um this paper called me zero uh introduces a way for memories to be
introduces a way for memories to be updated as well. Um so the way that this
updated as well. Um so the way that this works is you'll have like messages
works is you'll have like messages coming in and um each time you get a
coming in and um each time you get a message, you'll apply a language model
message, you'll apply a language model to extract some memories from it. um
to extract some memories from it. um some like potential facts that you might
some like potential facts that you might want to store or update and you'll have
want to store or update and you'll have an external uh database store um and
an external uh database store um and you'll try to check and see do I have
you'll try to check and see do I have anything in that database store that's
anything in that database store that's relevant to these um facts that I pulled
relevant to these um facts that I pulled out of these messages. So you'll
out of these messages. So you'll retrieve the top K and to do this you'll
retrieve the top K and to do this you'll use like an embedding based retriever
use like an embedding based retriever model like you know the ones we talked
model like you know the ones we talked about a little bit ago. um you'll pull
about a little bit ago. um you'll pull out similar facts like um six flags for
out similar facts like um six flags for example or like um I work at X and
example or like um I work at X and you'll apply a language model to check
you'll apply a language model to check for all of these extracted memories from
for all of these extracted memories from these latest messages um do they um are
these latest messages um do they um are they present in these similar retrieved
they present in these similar retrieved memories? If they're not present then we
memories? If they're not present then we should potentially add them in. um if
should potentially add them in. um if they are an update to something that's
they are an update to something that's there, we should replace what's stored
there, we should replace what's stored for that with the new thing. If it
for that with the new thing. If it negates something that's already there,
negates something that's already there, like for example, you say, "I work at
like for example, you say, "I work at X," but then later on you say, "I got
X," but then later on you say, "I got laid off," you might want to just delete
laid off," you might want to just delete that fact rather than um than updating
that fact rather than um than updating it. Um or if it's not relevant at all,
it. Um or if it's not relevant at all, you would just ignore it.
you would just ignore it. And um I'll refer you to details or for
And um I'll refer you to details or for the paper for for details about this um
the paper for for details about this um because the details also change with
because the details also change with with agentive systems but I think the
with agentive systems but I think the idea that um it's useful to be able to
idea that um it's useful to be able to like update knowledge as well if you
like update knowledge as well if you have conflicts is potentially pretty
have conflicts is potentially pretty useful.
useful. So, um, does anybody remember something
So, um, does anybody remember something from the lecture on context management
from the lecture on context management that had a similar goal to this being
that had a similar goal to this being able to update or delete memory?
able to update or delete memory? Yeah.
Yeah. Uh, hashing.
Uh, hashing. >> Yeah. Yeah. Basically, does anybody
>> Yeah. Yeah. Basically, does anybody remember the specific paper?
Yeah. Yeah, it's hashing in the sense that there we had like key values and
that there we had like key values and queries, right? Um and we were like
queries, right? Um and we were like storing values which were vectors. Um
storing values which were vectors. Um here we're storing like text um as
here we're storing like text um as facts.
Yeah. So the Delta paper actually did this,
So the Delta paper actually did this, right? like um linear attention is only
right? like um linear attention is only able to append um values to your um
able to append um values to your um what's effectively your memory but Delta
what's effectively your memory but Delta um uh like effectively retrieves um
um uh like effectively retrieves um things that are stored for particular
things that are stored for particular queries and then changes them changes
queries and then changes them changes the vectors that are stored for for them
the vectors that are stored for for them and that helps improve performance. So
and that helps improve performance. So this is sort of like a textbased analog
this is sort of like a textbased analog of that that has a similar goal.
of that that has a similar goal. Yeah, you could also think about like um
Yeah, you could also think about like um for the third type of learning for
for the third type of learning for updating the weights of a model, it's
updating the weights of a model, it's potentially helpful there to be able to
potentially helpful there to be able to forget stuff also. Um especially if you
forget stuff also. Um especially if you have kind of like conflicting knowledge
have kind of like conflicting knowledge and and people are starting to develop
and and people are starting to develop some approaches for that like unlearning
some approaches for that like unlearning um is one way to do it.
Okay, so those are some foundational papers about memory um that were
papers about memory um that were developed for assistance
developed for assistance for agents. Um feedback on trajectories
for agents. Um feedback on trajectories can be really useful. So this paper
can be really useful. So this paper called reflection was um a really
called reflection was um a really impactful it's a really uh it's a really
impactful it's a really uh it's a really pretty simple but effective um the way
pretty simple but effective um the way to get agents to use feedback and
to get agents to use feedback and potentially do better. So, it's
potentially do better. So, it's definitely worth knowing about. It's a
definitely worth knowing about. It's a good thing to implement if you're
good thing to implement if you're working on a project that might want an
working on a project that might want an agent to be able to benefit from its
agent to be able to benefit from its past experiences. Um, and the way it
past experiences. Um, and the way it works is we're trying to improve the
works is we're trying to improve the performance of an agent given multiple
performance of an agent given multiple attempts on a particular task. So, say
attempts on a particular task. So, say that you're asking the agent to like um,
that you're asking the agent to like um, you know, search for a product on a
you know, search for a product on a website. It makes one attempt at it. um
website. It makes one attempt at it. um it says that it's finished and you're
it says that it's finished and you're able to get some feedback about whether
able to get some feedback about whether it was likely correct or not. So that
it was likely correct or not. So that could come from like a person looking at
could come from like a person looking at it. It could come from applying a model
it. It could come from applying a model as a judge. Um but given that feedback,
as a judge. Um but given that feedback, you'll want the model to try again and
you'll want the model to try again and try to do better.
try to do better. And what this paper does is show that
And what this paper does is show that natural language feedback um on the
natural language feedback um on the attempt can be a really helpful thing
attempt can be a really helpful thing for the model to condition on in its
for the model to condition on in its second attempt. So like if it's trying
second attempt. So like if it's trying to answer this question about what was a
to answer this question about what was a particular series of battles, it might
particular series of battles, it might just mention one particular battle and
just mention one particular battle and then the feedback that's given um
then the feedback that's given um generated by a language model based on
generated by a language model based on knowing this is incorrect and looking at
knowing this is incorrect and looking at the question and the answer might be um
the question and the answer might be um you gave just a single battle rather
you gave just a single battle rather than a series. So as you can imagine
than a series. So as you can imagine this would be really helpful feedback
this would be really helpful feedback for the model to condition on as it you
for the model to condition on as it you know does another attempt at this task
know does another attempt at this task and it can get it correct. Um and the
and it can get it correct. Um and the paper shows that you know conditioning
paper shows that you know conditioning on this natural language description of
on this natural language description of what went wrong can be really helpful.
what went wrong can be really helpful. So we can generalize this also to um the
So we can generalize this also to um the agent improving as it does different
agent improving as it does different tasks. Right? This is improving on the
tasks. Right? This is improving on the same task. But you could imagine um
same task. But you could imagine um feedback might be generally helpful to
feedback might be generally helpful to improve performance on similar tasks as
improve performance on similar tasks as long as the feedback's like sufficiently
long as the feedback's like sufficiently general.
And the final way that we can like um have agents uh improve or you know kind
have agents uh improve or you know kind of the final foundational thing for
of the final foundational thing for helping agents improve um is remembering
helping agents improve um is remembering trajectories uh like entire
trajectories uh like entire trajectories, entire episodes that
trajectories, entire episodes that they've done in the past and using that
they've done in the past and using that to shape what they do on future tasks.
to shape what they do on future tasks. There is a bunch of papers that have
There is a bunch of papers that have done this. We have some links to them at
done this. We have some links to them at the bottom of this slide. Um, but the
the bottom of this slide. Um, but the key thing in all of them is you'll have
key thing in all of them is you'll have some collection of like training tasks
some collection of like training tasks and those tasks could be like a
and those tasks could be like a collection of demonstrations or they
collection of demonstrations or they could be produced by the agent as it's
could be produced by the agent as it's carrying out tasks one at a time. Um,
carrying out tasks one at a time. Um, and you'll pull all of those tasks
and you'll pull all of those tasks together. Maybe you'll additionally like
together. Maybe you'll additionally like um generate some text that describes uh
um generate some text that describes uh feedback from them sort of like
feedback from them sort of like reflection did on the last slide. And
reflection did on the last slide. And you'll have that pool of experiences.
you'll have that pool of experiences. And then when you get a new task um that
And then when you get a new task um that comes in, you'll retrieve from this uh
comes in, you'll retrieve from this uh set of trajectories and um maybe
set of trajectories and um maybe generated text about them to find
generated text about them to find something that's relevant for the task
something that's relevant for the task that you're carrying out. You'll put it
that you're carrying out. You'll put it in the context window of your model and
in the context window of your model and it'll generally help you to do better.
it'll generally help you to do better. Um so this is sort of like rag for
Um so this is sort of like rag for agents, right? Um and uh it's pretty
agents, right? Um and uh it's pretty effective.
effective. Any questions about this?
Yeah. >> What do you mean by trajectory in this
>> What do you mean by trajectory in this case is like sequence of calls.
case is like sequence of calls. >> Yeah. Yeah. So a trajectory generally
>> Yeah. Yeah. So a trajectory generally for an agent is the sequence of um like
for an agent is the sequence of um like messages that it gets from the
messages that it gets from the environment or the user. So the
environment or the user. So the observations um the actions that it
observations um the actions that it takes like the tool calls and um and uh
takes like the tool calls and um and uh potentially also you know the chains of
potentially also you know the chains of thought that it produces. So one way to
thought that it produces. So one way to think about it is basically just like
think about it is basically just like all the sequence of um of uh messages um
all the sequence of um of uh messages um in the context window of the model
in the context window of the model >> and you retrieve it by image
>> and you retrieve it by image differently. You can do this regular
differently. You can do this regular embedding retrieval or compare to
embedding retrieval or compare to process sequences and do some set
process sequences and do some set comparison.
comparison. >> Yeah. What are the different ways that
>> Yeah. What are the different ways that you could do retrieval? So typically you
you could do retrieval? So typically you want the model to you're giving the
want the model to you're giving the model the description of a new task that
model the description of a new task that it should carry out. So you have just
it should carry out. So you have just that text description and you'll embed
that text description and you'll embed that um with an embedding model and
that um with an embedding model and you'll retrieve um based on the
you'll retrieve um based on the descriptions of other tasks that each
descriptions of other tasks that each have like a trajectory associated with
have like a trajectory associated with them and maybe you'll also constrain
them and maybe you'll also constrain that to be like we'll just retrieve the
that to be like we'll just retrieve the tasks for this particular domain that
tasks for this particular domain that we're working in. Um yeah, good
we're working in. Um yeah, good question. Any other questions about this
question. Any other questions about this approach? Generally, this is sort of
approach? Generally, this is sort of like a whole class of approaches. Um
like a whole class of approaches. Um there's different ways to instantiate
there's different ways to instantiate it. Um the details like how do you build
it. Um the details like how do you build up the experiences? How do you do the
up the experiences? How do you do the retrieval? Um but just want to kind of
retrieval? Um but just want to kind of give you a sense that if we have past
give you a sense that if we have past successful trajectories and we show
successful trajectories and we show those as examples to the agent, it can
those as examples to the agent, it can help it to do better.
Okay. So with that we kind of have the foundation for talking about um actually
foundation for talking about um actually inducing skills. Um so
inducing skills. Um so we can think about skills as being like
we can think about skills as being like parts of a task that are reusable across
parts of a task that are reusable across different tasks. So at the very
different tasks. So at the very beginning we talked about like searching
beginning we talked about like searching for a product and that might look
for a product and that might look something like we tell the agent show me
something like we tell the agent show me results for this particular query and
results for this particular query and the agent might produce a chain of
the agent might produce a chain of thought like this and then it might
thought like this and then it might produce these particular actions that
produce these particular actions that actually interact with the web page like
actually interact with the web page like um uh clicking on this element
um uh clicking on this element identified by this particular ID which
identified by this particular ID which is the search box typing a query in
is the search box typing a query in there and and clicking on another
there and and clicking on another element which is like the actual button
element which is like the actual button to search.
to search. And this uh chunk of a task might be
And this uh chunk of a task might be reused on future tasks. Like if I say
reused on future tasks. Like if I say what is the price range for um this
what is the price range for um this particular item, it might need to do
particular item, it might need to do these same exact steps again as well as
these same exact steps again as well as some additional ones afterwards.
some additional ones afterwards. And so we can think of a skill as being
And so we can think of a skill as being um a specific like reused part of the
um a specific like reused part of the task.
task. Is this a good way to represent a skill?
Can anybody think of any issues with this?
just >> Yeah,
that's right. Yeah. So, like if the element ids on the page change, the
element ids on the page change, the skill will break. And you know, there's
skill will break. And you know, there's a number of ways that that could happen.
a number of ways that that could happen. Like, you know, maybe the elements are
Like, you know, maybe the elements are maybe it's the same page, but things are
maybe it's the same page, but things are just numbered differently. You can make
just numbered differently. You can make some changes to the action space to deal
some changes to the action space to deal with that. I think JY will talk about
with that. I think JY will talk about that in his lecture. But like if we go
that in his lecture. But like if we go to a different website that has like a
to a different website that has like a different search interface um it's going
different search interface um it's going to break and we'll see some examples of
to break and we'll see some examples of that later on.
Yeah. So we'll generally compare as Graham said text versus code as ways to
Graham said text versus code as ways to represent skills.
represent skills. I want to briefly highlight some uh
I want to briefly highlight some uh really cool papers um from the past that
really cool papers um from the past that I think kind of like lay a foundation
I think kind of like lay a foundation for skill induction um for learning
for skill induction um for learning skills from experience. Uh, one is
skills from experience. Uh, one is called um Voyager and um they're
called um Voyager and um they're controlling an agent in Minecraft. Um,
controlling an agent in Minecraft. Um, and they're using uh code as a way to
and they're using uh code as a way to control the agent where the code
control the agent where the code functions um implement things like um
functions um implement things like um crafting a particular item or combating
crafting a particular item or combating a zombie. And representing these like
a zombie. And representing these like subtasks as functions allows functions
subtasks as functions allows functions to call each other. So that as the agent
to call each other. So that as the agent like learns functions for simple things,
like learns functions for simple things, it can then like compose them calling
it can then like compose them calling them in other functions and you can
them in other functions and you can carry out increasingly complex tasks.
carry out increasingly complex tasks. There's also a line of work um from the
There's also a line of work um from the program induction community um that that
program induction community um that that does this. I think a really nice
does this. I think a really nice representative of this is um uh work
representative of this is um uh work called dreamcoder and a few papers that
called dreamcoder and a few papers that built on it. And there you're um sort of
built on it. And there you're um sort of uh you have basically like grammarss
uh you have basically like grammarss over things that you're constructing um
over things that you're constructing um like objects um and you uh like have uh
like objects um and you uh like have uh some examples of complete objects which
some examples of complete objects which are constructed using like very
are constructed using like very low-level functions and you search for
low-level functions and you search for recurrent patterns in that you find
recurrent patterns in that you find patterns that can be abstracted into
patterns that can be abstracted into functions and you do that repeatedly and
functions and you do that repeatedly and you're sort of like compressing the
you're sort of like compressing the programs that construct these objects.
programs that construct these objects. And then there's also some follow-ups to
And then there's also some follow-ups to this that uh integrate like large
this that uh integrate like large language models, Python code, and uh
language models, Python code, and uh natural language descriptions too.
natural language descriptions too. And some of the same ideas in those
And some of the same ideas in those papers are also useful for agents that
papers are also useful for agents that are um using language models to interact
are um using language models to interact with the world. A typical way that we'll
with the world. A typical way that we'll evaluate systems for inducing and using
evaluate systems for inducing and using skills is an online learning setting. So
skills is an online learning setting. So when you're interacting with um an
when you're interacting with um an agent, you are maybe having it carry out
agent, you are maybe having it carry out a bunch of tasks in succession and some
a bunch of tasks in succession and some of those tasks are going to be similar
of those tasks are going to be similar to each other. You want the system to be
to each other. You want the system to be able to learn from your interactions
able to learn from your interactions with it and then be able to do better in
with it and then be able to do better in the future, right? So um this is an
the future, right? So um this is an online learning setting where we'll have
online learning setting where we'll have tasks come in one at a time. So for
tasks come in one at a time. So for example, like you might say, add a Sony
example, like you might say, add a Sony Bluetooth headphone to my wish list. And
Bluetooth headphone to my wish list. And we'll be building up a memory of skills
we'll be building up a memory of skills um incrementally as we solve those
um incrementally as we solve those tasks. So um there will be an induction
tasks. So um there will be an induction step that we'll talk about in a slide or
step that we'll talk about in a slide or two. And that induction step will
two. And that induction step will create a skill like search for a product
create a skill like search for a product and add a product to the wish list that
and add a product to the wish list that are useful for solving this particular
are useful for solving this particular task.
task. And um you know maybe we have another
And um you know maybe we have another one like this task here and we can apply
one like this task here and we can apply those skills on future tasks like this
those skills on future tasks like this task might also involve searching for a
task might also involve searching for a product and hopefully we'll do better on
product and hopefully we'll do better on that task given that we had this skill
that task given that we had this skill induced from the previous task
induced from the previous task and so on. So what we're interested in
and so on. So what we're interested in is if we can measure success on each of
is if we can measure success on each of these tasks, is our success rate like
these tasks, is our success rate like getting better and better? Are we able
getting better and better? Are we able to solve increasingly complex tasks um
to solve increasingly complex tasks um as we're learning from experience and
as we're learning from experience and building up um uh representations of the
building up um uh representations of the ways to do these simpler tasks? Any
ways to do these simpler tasks? Any questions about this setting?
So the papers that we'll look at for the rest of the lecture look at sort of
rest of the lecture look at sort of different parts of this space of um uh
different parts of this space of um uh learning skills from experience having
learning skills from experience having this library and ask questions about
this library and ask questions about what should we do with the skills like
what should we do with the skills like after we've um induced them. So there's
after we've um induced them. So there's generally like a learning step where
generally like a learning step where we'll have these uh tasks coming in.
we'll have these uh tasks coming in. We'll try to get a skill out of them.
We'll try to get a skill out of them. will decide whether to store that skill
will decide whether to store that skill um in the memory that we're building up
um in the memory that we're building up over time. There's um the step of like
over time. There's um the step of like actually using this memory of skills to
actually using this memory of skills to potentially improve performance on the
potentially improve performance on the tasks that we're carrying out. And then
tasks that we're carrying out. And then finally, we might want to, you know, if
finally, we might want to, you know, if we're getting too many skills, we might
we're getting too many skills, we might want to try to simplify those, like
want to try to simplify those, like delete the ones that aren't being used,
delete the ones that aren't being used, or if they're too specific, we might
or if they're too specific, we might want to make them more general. um or
want to make them more general. um or like consolidate and merge multiple
like consolidate and merge multiple things together.
things together. [clears throat]
We'll go a little bit deeper into one paper um that I think is pretty
paper um that I think is pretty representative of ways for inducing
representative of ways for inducing skills. Uh it was also done here at CMU
skills. Uh it was also done here at CMU as work led by Zora Wong who will be
as work led by Zora Wong who will be giving a guest lecture on some other
giving a guest lecture on some other topics a little bit later on in the
topics a little bit later on in the course. Um but this paper's called agent
course. Um but this paper's called agent workflow memory and um the way it works
workflow memory and um the way it works is it we applied it to web tasks. Uh
is it we applied it to web tasks. Uh this is work with with Graham also um
this is work with with Graham also um and me and uh we applied this to web
and me and uh we applied this to web tasks and you have a query like this and
tasks and you have a query like this and you know tell me the number of reviews
you know tell me the number of reviews that our store received so far and when
that our store received so far and when the agent's carrying this out these are
the agent's carrying this out these are the actual tool calls that it'll
the actual tool calls that it'll produce.
produce. So we have this sequence of tool calls
So we have this sequence of tool calls and we want to try to identify which
and we want to try to identify which parts of this might be potentially
parts of this might be potentially reusable in the future
reusable in the future and you can probably guess how we do
and you can probably guess how we do this. We ask a language model to take a
this. We ask a language model to take a look at the sequence of tool calls and
look at the sequence of tool calls and identify ones that seem like they might
identify ones that seem like they might be useful on future tasks.
And we'll have the model output what we call workflows um which are sort of like
call workflows um which are sort of like a textbased representation of skills
a textbased representation of skills text and actions. And a workflow will
text and actions. And a workflow will have like a description of the subtask
have like a description of the subtask like searching for a particular item.
like searching for a particular item. And then um it'll have the sequence of
And then um it'll have the sequence of actions that you use to do that. And
actions that you use to do that. And we're having the model make this a
we're having the model make this a little bit more general so that it could
little bit more general so that it could apply to like searching for other terms.
apply to like searching for other terms. So we have it use like create a template
So we have it use like create a template that can abstract out some parts of the
that can abstract out some parts of the um initial action sequence. You might be
um initial action sequence. You might be thinking like this is starting to look
thinking like this is starting to look like code, right? That's true. Um and a
like code, right? That's true. Um and a little bit later on we'll compare code
little bit later on we'll compare code to this also and show how that can be
to this also and show how that can be better in some ways but also uh make
better in some ways but also uh make things a little bit more uh fragile.
things a little bit more uh fragile. A pretty important part of this is we'll
A pretty important part of this is we'll um apply a judge model to this
um apply a judge model to this trajectory to decide um have the judge
trajectory to decide um have the judge predict whether the trajectory seem to
predict whether the trajectory seem to be correct or not. And we'll use that to
be correct or not. And we'll use that to determine whether we should actually add
determine whether we should actually add the workflows that were induced to the
the workflows that were induced to the memory. Um because we don't want to be
memory. Um because we don't want to be um remembering things that were
um remembering things that were incorrect because those might steer the
incorrect because those might steer the model wrong in the future.
model wrong in the future. >> Any questions about this?
Okay. And so
so the way that we'll um give the model
the way that we'll um give the model access to these uh collection of
access to these uh collection of workflows um is just by sticking them in
workflows um is just by sticking them in the context window of the model. So this
the context window of the model. So this looks a lot like you know this agent
looks a lot like you know this agent skill standard. Um you have choices
skill standard. Um you have choices about whether you show everything or
about whether you show everything or whether you show just you know kind of
whether you show just you know kind of the text description. um and what you do
the text description. um and what you do there could depend on how many skills
there could depend on how many skills you have and you know the context length
you have and you know the context length of the model.
So um for the sake of time I I'll skip over this induction prompt but we do
over this induction prompt but we do find that um having this memory of like
find that um having this memory of like past uh subtasks um can help to improve
past uh subtasks um can help to improve the performance of the agent as it's
the performance of the agent as it's learning online. So on the x-axis here
learning online. So on the x-axis here we have like um different tasks in a
we have like um different tasks in a fixed ordering from this benchmark
fixed ordering from this benchmark involving interacting with like a map
involving interacting with like a map tool and the blue line here is the
tool and the blue line here is the baseline agent that doesn't have a
baseline agent that doesn't have a memory that sort of converges to around
memory that sort of converges to around you know like 10% accuracy on these
you know like 10% accuracy on these tasks and the labels here are the tasks
tasks and the labels here are the tasks that are being solved by the agent
that are being solved by the agent correctly. Um and then this black line
correctly. Um and then this black line which adds in this memory of um subtasks
which adds in this memory of um subtasks improves pretty substantially and it's
improves pretty substantially and it's able to um you know this gap emerges
able to um you know this gap emerges between the two but it's also able to
between the two but it's also able to carry out these like increasingly
carry out these like increasingly complex tasks eventually doing things
complex tasks eventually doing things like you know finding a hotel near this
like you know finding a hotel near this location showing me the walking path um
location showing me the walking path um that the baseline agent just isn't able
that the baseline agent just isn't able to do.
So this is using, you know, sort of this mix of text and example actions to
mix of text and example actions to represent skills.
represent skills. But we could also consider using code,
But we could also consider using code, right? And both of these are
right? And both of these are implementations of a search product um
implementations of a search product um function. And
function. And if we're using just this text and
if we're using just this text and examples, this is going to be in the
examples, this is going to be in the context window of the model. and then
context window of the model. and then it's going to be needing to produce
it's going to be needing to produce these tool calls um in a new context,
these tool calls um in a new context, right? As it tries to carry out the same
right? As it tries to carry out the same subtask. So, it's flexible like the
subtask. So, it's flexible like the model could choose to insert a
model could choose to insert a particular search term to search for a
particular search term to search for a different product. If the website has
different product. If the website has changed and we no longer have like this
changed and we no longer have like this particular um element for the search
particular um element for the search box, then the agent could choose to use
box, then the agent could choose to use the correct one instead. Um, but it also
the correct one instead. Um, but it also means that the agent needs to like
means that the agent needs to like actually produce all of those tool calls
actually produce all of those tool calls itself. If we're using code, the agent
itself. If we're using code, the agent could actually just call this function
could actually just call this function as a tool, right? If it passes in the
as a tool, right? If it passes in the right arguments and if the functions
right arguments and if the functions correct, then it doesn't have to do
correct, then it doesn't have to do anything. It doesn't have to produce all
anything. It doesn't have to produce all of those low-level actions itself. Um,
of those low-level actions itself. Um, the tool will just do that as it
the tool will just do that as it executes in the environment. Can anybody
executes in the environment. Can anybody think of uh some pros and cons of using
think of uh some pros and cons of using a function like this as a representation
a function like this as a representation for a skill?
>> It's very rigid. >> Yeah, it is very rigid. So like um the
>> Yeah, it is very rigid. So like um the model will need to the model calling
model will need to the model calling this tool will do exactly these three
this tool will do exactly these three steps and there's no room to to deviate
steps and there's no room to to deviate from it. Um yes that's a main call
from it. Um yes that's a main call that's a main like con to it but we also
that's a main like con to it but we also get a lot of the pros of using code
get a lot of the pros of using code right so like we can nest functions it
right so like we can nest functions it can be hierarchical we can actually like
can be hierarchical we can actually like generate test cases for that specific
generate test cases for that specific function too independent from the entire
function too independent from the entire trajectory that it's executed in. And we
trajectory that it's executed in. And we can do things like you know refactoring
can do things like you know refactoring also.
also. So uh Zora has another paper um called
So uh Zora has another paper um called inducing programmatic skills or agent
inducing programmatic skills or agent skill induction which um which do this
skill induction which um which do this and it looks pretty similar to the
and it looks pretty similar to the approach we were using to induce these
approach we were using to induce these textual workflows. So you have a
textual workflows. So you have a trajectory like this with these tool
trajectory like this with these tool calls and we'll have the language model
calls and we'll have the language model um we'll we'll just use the fact that
um we'll we'll just use the fact that language models are also good at
language models are also good at generating code and we'll um prompt the
generating code and we'll um prompt the model to generate functions which
model to generate functions which abstract a lot of the um uh behaviors in
abstract a lot of the um uh behaviors in this trajectory and these are real
this trajectory and these are real examples. So the language model will
examples. So the language model will write this search reviews function and
write this search reviews function and um a doc string for it and then you know
um a doc string for it and then you know it has these low-level tool calls as um
it has these low-level tool calls as um lines in the function. This other one
lines in the function. This other one for open marketing reviews but we'll
for open marketing reviews but we'll also have it generate sort of a rewrite
also have it generate sort of a rewrite of this original trajectory that uses
of this original trajectory that uses those tools. So a really nice thing
those tools. So a really nice thing about um code is that we can test it by
about um code is that we can test it by executing it. So instead of applying the
executing it. So instead of applying the judge to the original trajectory like we
judge to the original trajectory like we did before, we can have the language
did before, we can have the language model. Well, we can execute this
model. Well, we can execute this generated abstracted code and then apply
generated abstracted code and then apply the judge to the end result that you get
the judge to the end result that you get from that. And if that appears to be
from that. And if that appears to be correct, that's sort of like a stronger
correct, that's sort of like a stronger indicator that the skills, these code
indicator that the skills, these code skills that you induced are also
skills that you induced are also correct.
correct. And if they are, then we put them in the
And if they are, then we put them in the memory and they become usable to the
memory and they become usable to the language model just as tools. So this is
language model just as tools. So this is a way of like building up a tool library
a way of like building up a tool library that the model's able to use on future
that the model's able to use on future examples and um we show that it also you
examples and um we show that it also you know improves performance.
Yeah. So a nice thing about um code skills is that they allow testing just
skills is that they allow testing just of the skill by itself. Um there's this
of the skill by itself. Um there's this nice paper called skillw weaver which
nice paper called skillw weaver which does this. Um, so this is sort of some
does this. Um, so this is sort of some pseudo code for the uh the loop that I
pseudo code for the uh the loop that I just showed you where you have a task,
just showed you where you have a task, you um propose some set of like code
you um propose some set of like code skills for it and then you'll try to use
skills for it and then you'll try to use those skills to execute the task. You'll
those skills to execute the task. You'll get an episode, you'll apply a reward
get an episode, you'll apply a reward model to it. Um, and if it succeeds,
model to it. Um, and if it succeeds, then you can put all those induced
then you can put all those induced skills into your memory. But if not,
skills into your memory. But if not, then you could make some revisions to
then you could make some revisions to it. And there's a number of ways that
it. And there's a number of ways that skills might not succeed, right? So, um,
skills might not succeed, right? So, um, one thing we could do is like apply a
one thing we could do is like apply a code llinter to an induced skill. So,
code llinter to an induced skill. So, here's a real example from the paper.
here's a real example from the paper. There's this induced skill called
There's this induced skill called identify pill. Um, you know, for like
identify pill. Um, you know, for like interacting with a drug website. And
interacting with a drug website. And this uh function like takes a lot of
this uh function like takes a lot of arguments like you know the um the make
arguments like you know the um the make of the pill the color but in the initial
of the pill the color but in the initial version of this skill that the agent
version of this skill that the agent wrote it actually didn't use all the
wrote it actually didn't use all the parameters. So like it ignored this
parameters. So like it ignored this color parameter. So you could get
color parameter. So you could get feedback from a llinter on this skill
feedback from a llinter on this skill and then sort of in the reflection type
and then sort of in the reflection type way um condition on that and then like
way um condition on that and then like you know uh create an updated version of
you know uh create an updated version of the function and store that or like try
the function and store that or like try executing that and store that. You could
executing that and store that. You could also use feedback from this reward model
also use feedback from this reward model and condition on that when you're um
and condition on that when you're um making these revisions to the skill 2.
making these revisions to the skill 2. So these are some nice benefits of code
So these are some nice benefits of code um that can be advantages even if you
um that can be advantages even if you know the actual code function itself is
know the actual code function itself is a bit more rigid.
Another nice benefit is that because these functions that are induced are now
these functions that are induced are now tool calls, it can really reduce the
tool calls, it can really reduce the number of times that your agent needs to
number of times that your agent needs to interact with the environment. So here's
interact with the environment. So here's an example from um Zora's uh ASI paper.
an example from um Zora's uh ASI paper. We have this uh task like uh updating a
We have this uh task like uh updating a couple addresses on a page and for the
couple addresses on a page and for the base agent you have to you know like do
base agent you have to you know like do all the very low-level actions of
all the very low-level actions of navigating through all these forms
navigating through all these forms typing the particular um things from the
typing the particular um things from the address. But if we have this model that
address. But if we have this model that has induced these code skills, you can
has induced these code skills, you can and this is a real example from uh from
and this is a real example from uh from the work where we induce this navigate
the work where we induce this navigate to address settings and update address
to address settings and update address details functions. We can actually solve
details functions. We can actually solve this task in three steps where we um you
this task in three steps where we um you know assuming that this is a good fit
know assuming that this is a good fit for the site. Um we can just call these
for the site. Um we can just call these two functions and um complete the task.
two functions and um complete the task. Um, and the agent is actually much
Um, and the agent is actually much faster because it doesn't need to
faster because it doesn't need to reobserve the website and then generate
reobserve the website and then generate the tool call, then reobserve the new
the tool call, then reobserve the new website, generate the new tool call. Um,
website, generate the new tool call. Um, as you'll probably see in the guey um,
as you'll probably see in the guey um, lecture that JY is giving, um, a really
lecture that JY is giving, um, a really big bottleneck for these models is
big bottleneck for these models is actually the number of times that they
actually the number of times that they have to interact with the site because
have to interact with the site because these images take up a lot of tokens and
these images take up a lot of tokens and actually producing a chain of thought
actually producing a chain of thought um, before each action takes up a lot of
um, before each action takes up a lot of tokens too. All of those have to be
tokens too. All of those have to be generated. So efficiency is really
generated. So efficiency is really important here.
important here. And um in this work we did find so we
And um in this work we did find so we did a controlled comparison between
did a controlled comparison between using text skills and code skills. This
using text skills and code skills. This was on a set of tasks which did have
was on a set of tasks which did have sort of more repeated structure. Um but
sort of more repeated structure. Um but we found that uh in comparison to no
we found that uh in comparison to no memory text skills um helped but code
memory text skills um helped but code skills helped even more in terms of you
skills helped even more in terms of you know the accuracy of the system but also
know the accuracy of the system but also we got pretty big improvements in
we got pretty big improvements in efficiency the number of times that the
efficiency the number of times that the agent needed to interact with the page.
Cool. So, as we've kind of talked about
So, as we've kind of talked about before, a big potential issue with
before, a big potential issue with skills is that they might not be
skills is that they might not be general. And here's a failure case of
general. And here's a failure case of this approach and actually a failure
this approach and actually a failure case of these code skills. So, we tried
case of these code skills. So, we tried to see how well could skills generalize
to see how well could skills generalize across websites. And we induced um these
across websites. And we induced um these code skills on one site uh and then we
code skills on one site uh and then we tried to apply them on a real website uh
tried to apply them on a real website uh like the Target shopping site. So this
like the Target shopping site. So this skill um that was induced on a different
skill um that was induced on a different site worked on that site but like um
site worked on that site but like um uses assumes that this uh this um
uses assumes that this uh this um particular element that you're
particular element that you're interacting with has a drop down like
interacting with has a drop down like this. Whereas on the target site it's
this. Whereas on the target site it's you know this set of radio buttons and
you know this set of radio buttons and so it it fails there. And um you have to
so it it fails there. And um you have to have the model be able to like actually
have the model be able to like actually edit the skill based on um feedback from
edit the skill based on um feedback from the environment as it's interacting with
the environment as it's interacting with it.
But code has a solution to this, right? Uh so we have um abstract classes and
Uh so we have um abstract classes and those can be instantiated in different
those can be instantiated in different ways. There's this uh paper called poly
ways. There's this uh paper called poly skill which does this. So um they're
skill which does this. So um they're using code as the representation sort of
using code as the representation sort of building on this ASI work that we did.
building on this ASI work that we did. Um, but the first time that the model
Um, but the first time that the model interacts with a new website, it writes
interacts with a new website, it writes an abstract class which doesn't have
an abstract class which doesn't have implementations for the methods, but
implementations for the methods, but could have stubs like searching for a
could have stubs like searching for a product, adding to a cart, checking out.
product, adding to a cart, checking out. And um, then it'll also write a website
And um, then it'll also write a website specific implementation of it like this
specific implementation of it like this one for Amazon. Then when it's
one for Amazon. Then when it's interacting with a different site, you
interacting with a different site, you could have some metadata or you could
could have some metadata or you could even just have the language model
even just have the language model trigger that this particular concrete
trigger that this particular concrete implementation no longer applies. and
implementation no longer applies. and then you'll write a different
then you'll write a different instantiation of the abstract class. And
instantiation of the abstract class. And they show that this helps too. Um, this
they show that this helps too. Um, this is also nice because it gives you a way
is also nice because it gives you a way to have like a large number of specific
to have like a large number of specific skills, but only have a subset of them
skills, but only have a subset of them be active at a given time that are
be active at a given time that are actually relevant. So, this kind of
actually relevant. So, this kind of makes sense, right? It's, you know, just
makes sense, right? It's, you know, just a software engineering best practice
a software engineering best practice that's also applied to agents.
Okay. Uh, yeah, we talked about all this already. um you guys had a good sense of
already. um you guys had a good sense of the the pros and cons of each of these
the the pros and cons of each of these types of representation, but it's
types of representation, but it's helpful to know that, you know, the
helpful to know that, you know, the skills standard allows you to combine
skills standard allows you to combine both and um there's a lot of research to
both and um there's a lot of research to be done on the best way to combine these
be done on the best way to combine these representations together. Um like uh
representations together. Um like uh said,
said, okay, so we'll go quickly through a few
okay, so we'll go quickly through a few papers um on different kind of like
papers um on different kind of like parts of this skill life cycle. This is
parts of this skill life cycle. This is a really open research topic of like
a really open research topic of like what are the best ways to induce and
what are the best ways to induce and manage these skills. Um you'll have the
manage these skills. Um you'll have the papers for for more details. Um but you
papers for for more details. Um but you can also explore this in your projects
can also explore this in your projects uh towards the end of the lecture or the
uh towards the end of the lecture or the end of the class if you're interested.
end of the class if you're interested. Everything we've talked about so far has
Everything we've talked about so far has been learning from success, but it's
been learning from success, but it's also potentially pretty helpful to learn
also potentially pretty helpful to learn from failures. So say that the model
from failures. So say that the model like tries to carry out this task like
like tries to carry out this task like um you know searching for Bluetooth
um you know searching for Bluetooth headphones. Um but for this particular
headphones. Um but for this particular website they sort of have like their
website they sort of have like their search terms are or rather than and so
search terms are or rather than and so you get a list of everything that's
you get a list of everything that's Bluetooth or headphones or a Sony. This
Bluetooth or headphones or a Sony. This is a real example from this reasoning
is a real example from this reasoning bench paper from Google. So you get like
bench paper from Google. So you get like 5,000 results and the agent just breaks
5,000 results and the agent just breaks on this like it has to pagionate through
on this like it has to pagionate through all of these 5,000 results. it does, you
all of these 5,000 results. it does, you know, it loses track of what the task is
know, it loses track of what the task is and it fails. But if we observe that um
and it fails. But if we observe that um failed trajectory sort of in the
failed trajectory sort of in the reflection style way, we could uh
reflection style way, we could uh produce some text that gives guidance on
produce some text that gives guidance on how to avoid it in the future. Like
how to avoid it in the future. Like saying um we should give a more specific
saying um we should give a more specific search term rather than this more
search term rather than this more general one and we should you know have
general one and we should you know have like a larger number of items displayed
like a larger number of items displayed so the model gets more in its context
so the model gets more in its context window at once. And this paper um
window at once. And this paper um generally uses the same framework as
generally uses the same framework as like uh agent workflow memory, agent
like uh agent workflow memory, agent skill induction, but instead of just
skill induction, but instead of just having these kind of abstractions of the
having these kind of abstractions of the correct trajectories, it generates this
correct trajectories, it generates this text feedback um which um is applicable
text feedback um which um is applicable to failed trajectories too and is also
to failed trajectories too and is also you know the kind of thing that you
you know the kind of thing that you would write in a skill yourself um if
would write in a skill yourself um if you were writing one
you were writing one and they find that this is pretty
and they find that this is pretty helpful. So these are different like
helpful. So these are different like types of memory. Um so synapse uses
types of memory. Um so synapse uses trajectories
trajectories like full trajectories with all of the
like full trajectories with all of the actions and observations all the tool
actions and observations all the tool calls and messages. Um this is agent
calls and messages. Um this is agent workflow memory that uses these slightly
workflow memory that uses these slightly abstracted parts of trajectories. And
abstracted parts of trajectories. And this is their approach that uses these
this is their approach that uses these text descriptions of strategies and um
text descriptions of strategies and um adding and negatives going you know
adding and negatives going you know adding and negative examples as inputs
adding and negative examples as inputs to the memory. um uh doesn't improve
to the memory. um uh doesn't improve performance when you're using either
performance when you're using either trajectories or
trajectories or um workflows, but does improve
um workflows, but does improve substantially when you have sort of
substantially when you have sort of these text descriptions, which kind of
these text descriptions, which kind of makes sense given the example we saw
makes sense given the example we saw before because you can describe in a
before because you can describe in a general way how not to fail
general way how not to fail rather than remembering and conditioning
rather than remembering and conditioning on those failures.
Another important thing to think about is we're deciding whether to store
is we're deciding whether to store trajectories um you know store things in
trajectories um you know store things in the memory or what type of strategies to
the memory or what type of strategies to infer from the examples based on whether
infer from the examples based on whether we judged the example to be successful
we judged the example to be successful or not. That's in most of this work
or not. That's in most of this work using a model as a judge that looks at
using a model as a judge that looks at the final state of the trajectory, looks
the final state of the trajectory, looks at the task that you were trying to
at the task that you were trying to solve and predicts does it seem like I
solve and predicts does it seem like I got it correct or not. So a really good
got it correct or not. So a really good question to ask here is what you know
question to ask here is what you know how much does the quality of that judge
how much does the quality of that judge affect the performance of the algorithm
affect the performance of the algorithm because we know the judges aren't
because we know the judges aren't perfect. Um this paper reasoning bank
perfect. Um this paper reasoning bank controlled for this. So they um run
controlled for this. So they um run their methods with a perfect judge. Um
their methods with a perfect judge. Um and they also like to so they use kind
and they also like to so they use kind of the ground truth knowledge of whether
of the ground truth knowledge of whether it succeeded or not. Um but then they
it succeeded or not. Um but then they add some noise into that and so you're
add some noise into that and so you're able to control um the accuracy the
able to control um the accuracy the simulated accuracy of judging this
simulated accuracy of judging this trajectory and the performance does fall
trajectory and the performance does fall off but they find there's kind of a
off but they find there's kind of a sweet spot where um you do get
sweet spot where um you do get improvements from the memory um and uh
improvements from the memory um and uh there's sort of a widish range of
there's sort of a widish range of accuracies where using the judge to
accuracies where using the judge to induce the memory is helpful but there's
induce the memory is helpful but there's definitely room to do future work here.
Okay. And uh yeah, with the last few minutes, um I want to come back to we
minutes, um I want to come back to we had a question before about does having
had a question before about does having more skills than are necessary um
more skills than are necessary um potentially hurt performance? And we
potentially hurt performance? And we also had a question about like um we're
also had a question about like um we're if we're retrieving skills from a set um
if we're retrieving skills from a set um does that retriever matter? Like does
does that retriever matter? Like does the quality of that retriever matter? So
the quality of that retriever matter? So um there were some nice ablation
um there were some nice ablation experiments in this reasoning bank paper
experiments in this reasoning bank paper that uh control um how many experiences
that uh control um how many experiences you are retrieving from the memory that
you are retrieving from the memory that you have and they show that performance
you have and they show that performance does fall out fall off as you have more
does fall out fall off as you have more available. Um so this could be because
available. Um so this could be because of a couple different factors. So um you
of a couple different factors. So um you know maybe you just haven't run your
know maybe you just haven't run your agent on that many tasks and maybe
agent on that many tasks and maybe there's nothing relevant in your memory.
there's nothing relevant in your memory. So putting more stuff in is just bound
So putting more stuff in is just bound to be irrelevant. That would be sort of
to be irrelevant. That would be sort of like just a fundamental limitation of
like just a fundamental limitation of this approach applied in that setting.
this approach applied in that setting. Right? You can only learn if there's
Right? You can only learn if there's some similarities between the things
some similarities between the things you're learning from and the things
you're learning from and the things you're applying to. But it could also be
you're applying to. But it could also be like a limitation of the model itself.
like a limitation of the model itself. Maybe the model gets thrown off by
Maybe the model gets thrown off by having more things available in the
having more things available in the context window. That could potentially
context window. That could potentially be fixed by training the model, right?
be fixed by training the model, right? To be better at not being distracted by
To be better at not being distracted by irrelevant context, to be better at
irrelevant context, to be better at reasoning about what's actually
reasoning about what's actually relevant.
And um yeah, it can also potentially be useful to uh explicitly reduce the size
useful to uh explicitly reduce the size of your memory um so that there's less
of your memory um so that there's less of a burden on the language model to
of a burden on the language model to select from the things that are in it.
select from the things that are in it. And um we did some work on this that
And um we did some work on this that sort of uses like a caching type
sort of uses like a caching type approach um that you just look and see
approach um that you just look and see how often has a particular item in your
how often has a particular item in your memory been used in the past um and if
memory been used in the past um and if it hasn't been used very frequently,
it hasn't been used very frequently, you'll drop it.
you'll drop it. And this can you know improve this
And this can you know improve this efficiency of the approaches quite a bit
efficiency of the approaches quite a bit because you don't have to put as much in
because you don't have to put as much in your context window but can also improve
your context window but can also improve their success if the models are getting
their success if the models are getting distracted by things that are
distracted by things that are irrelevant.
Yeah. And the very last thing that we'll cover is so all of this was in some ways
cover is so all of this was in some ways a little bit ad hoc, right? Like we were
a little bit ad hoc, right? Like we were just having the language model look at
just having the language model look at these past experiences and then produce
these past experiences and then produce a skill which would be put in the memory
a skill which would be put in the memory and used in the future. But we're just
and used in the future. But we're just like prompting the language model to
like prompting the language model to predict things that seem like they might
predict things that seem like they might be useful in the future. And a really
be useful in the future. And a really natural question is could you just train
natural question is could you just train the language model to do that directly?
the language model to do that directly? Um you can. Um this is a direction
Um you can. Um this is a direction that's starting to be explored just
that's starting to be explored just really recently. So these papers um are
really recently. So these papers um are just appearing at you know just appeared
just appearing at you know just appeared at ACL um this year. But the basic idea
at ACL um this year. But the basic idea here is that we're going to do
here is that we're going to do reinforcement learning over multiple
reinforcement learning over multiple tasks seen in sequence. So this online
tasks seen in sequence. So this online learning setting that we've been
learning setting that we've been covering for evaluation, we're also
covering for evaluation, we're also going to run training on it. We'll get
going to run training on it. We'll get multiple similar tasks in sequence and
multiple similar tasks in sequence and we'll be building up the memory. um in
we'll be building up the memory. um in the same way that we've been doing
the same way that we've been doing before by inducing skills from the
before by inducing skills from the experience and using the memory on the
experience and using the memory on the future tasks. So this is a very complex,
future tasks. So this is a very complex, you know, process, right? Like we're
you know, process, right? Like we're using a couple different models here. Uh
using a couple different models here. Uh we're storing things in a memory. We're
we're storing things in a memory. We're retrieving those. We're using them. But
retrieving those. We're using them. But the good thing is reinforcement learning
the good thing is reinforcement learning doesn't care. You can just apply
doesn't care. You can just apply reinforcement learning to complex
reinforcement learning to complex non-ifferiable processes like this.
non-ifferiable processes like this. We'll have a couple lectures that show
We'll have a couple lectures that show you how. Um and you can get reward from
you how. Um and you can get reward from uh
uh did this second task succeed and did it
did this second task succeed and did it use tasks that were induced in the past.
use tasks that were induced in the past. So you can just do reinforcement
So you can just do reinforcement learning on this reward being trained on
learning on this reward being trained on um skill induction on sequences of
um skill induction on sequences of similar tasks. And um there's a couple
similar tasks. And um there's a couple papers that have explored this. They
papers that have explored this. They both find that this is helpful. And uh
both find that this is helpful. And uh one of them had this interesting result
one of them had this interesting result that um it helps to improve success if
that um it helps to improve success if you also include this reward term that
you also include this reward term that incentivizes reuse of the skills. So you
incentivizes reuse of the skills. So you could also imagine like introducing
could also imagine like introducing other sorts of reward terms that like
other sorts of reward terms that like minimize the size of the skill libraries
minimize the size of the skill libraries that you've induced to try to you know
that you've induced to try to you know kind of keep things regularized and not
kind of keep things regularized and not overfit too much. Um I think there's a
overfit too much. Um I think there's a lot of interesting like feature work
lot of interesting like feature work that could be explored here.
that could be explored here. And um yeah that's uh that's all the
And um yeah that's uh that's all the time that we have. Uh but uh hopefully
time that we have. Uh but uh hopefully you got a sense for the way that skills
you got a sense for the way that skills are induced and also written. Um you'll
are induced and also written. Um you'll apply those in your projects and you can
apply those in your projects and you can explore them in the research projects
explore them in the research projects too. I'll stick around for a few minutes
too. I'll stick around for a few minutes if folks have any questions.